Inventory of the Paul C. Domke audiovisual materials
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul C. Domke audiovisual materials
1936-1945
78027
Hoover Institution Archives
8 motion picture film reels, 1 envelope (0.9 linear feet)
Films and photographs, depicting missionary schools in China, 1936-1937; the effects of Japanese bombing in China, 1939; the transport of a giant panda from China to the St. Louis Zoo, 1939; scenes at Angkor Wat, 1939; the United States Observer Mission to Yenan, 1944-1945; American army headquarters in Chungking, 1945; and various other scenes in China, 1936-1945.
Domke, Paul C.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Teacher, Carleton College-in-China, 1937-1939; member, United States Observer Mission to Yenan, 1944-1945.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains films and photographs, depicting missionary schools in China, 1936-1937; the effects of Japanese bombing in China, 1939; the transport of a giant panda from China to the St. Louis Zoo, 1939; scenes at Angkor Wat, 1939; the United States Observer Mission to Yenan, 1944-1945; American army headquarters in Chungking, 1945; and various other scenes in China, 1936-1945. Titles for films taken from film canister labels.
United States. Observer Mission to Yenan, 1944-1945--Pictorial works.; Cambodia--Pictorial works.; China--Pictorial works.; Education--China--Pictorial works.; Motion pictures.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945--Pictorial works.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Pictorial works.
- Photographs, 1945 (Envelope A)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains 1 print of Paul Domke, Dr. Ma Hai-teh (George Hatem), K'e Po-nien, Huang Hua; 1 print of Gen. Chu Te, Mao Tse-tung; Col. Ivan Yeaton, Gen. Chen-chen, and U.S. Ambassador Patrick Hurley; 3 prints of scenes and people. All photographs taken in Yenan, China, 1945
- Motion picture films, 1936-1945
  - "Yangtze Gorges, Ichang to Chunking", August 1938 (Film Shelf)
  - "Angkor Wat, Hong Kong Harbor and Macau Peninsula", July 1939 (Film Shelf)
  - "Mdme. Chiang's Warphanage and PCD at CBI HQ in Chungking", 1938 & February 1944 to April 1945 (Film Shelf)
    1. Mdme. Chiang Kai-shek's "War orphanages" in Sian, Shensi, fall of 1938. These shots taken in the courtyard of the English Baptist Compound in the Tung-Kwan (east suburb) of Sian. 2. The river fording scenes are on the Wei River, north and east of Sian, near Fen Ling-tu. 3. Paul C. Domke mounting the steps of the Headquarters of CBI in Chungking on first visit in preparation for Dixie Mission (before it's aborted). 4. Next several scenes are taken at the Infantry Training Center's Officer's Quarters and Mess Hall in Kweilin Kwanghsi. Swimming in the Kuei River which joins the West River at Wuchow, near the border of Kwanghsi and Kwangtung. The medical officers of the ITC with Domke, Dr. Gentry, Capt. Stelle, Lt. Dadian, Dr. Pomerantz, Sgt. Cary, Sgt. Remenih, Dr. Ma Hai Te, Dr. Doherty, etc. on Kuei River bank where quarters were built. Next few scenes are of the Chinese Army students at the Signal School with Lt. Smith, one of the instructors. Summits near the camp mounted with anti-aircraft weapons. Yenan: General Chu-Tel Yeh Chien-ying, Huang Hua, Domke and Capt. Dolan coming out of Chu-Teh's cave after interview. Yenan Airstrip, Domke saying goodbye to some members of B-29 crew which came out with him and the 8th Route Army from behind Japanese lines in April, 1945. B-25 fighters on Yenan Airstrip. Dixie Mission after lunch front of Whittlesey Hall, Yenan.
    Access
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 78027_f_0012803.
  - "Typical Day at Ming-I Middle School, Fenyang, Shansi", 1936-1937 (Film Shelf)
  - "River boat trip up Yangtze Gorges, Ichang to Chunking", August 1938 (Film Shelf)
  - "Movement of Ming Hsien and Ming-I Middle Schools, Sian to Mien-Hsien to Chin T'ang", November 1938 to April 1939 (Film Shelf)
  - "Scenes of the Red Basin at Kwan-hsien, and out on Chengtu Plain; University of Chengtu, Szechwan; aftermath of Japanese bomber raid", May 1939 (Film Shelf)
  - "Activities at Ming Hsien, Taiku, Shansi; experimental farm scenes, etc", undated (Film Shelf)
  - "Chinese Giant Panda 'Pao Pei'", June 1939 to August 1939 (Film Shelf)
    Initial scenes photographed in Chengtu, Szechwan. Mr. Charles Schultz, owner, putting Pao-Pei through his paces in his front yard, on campus of West China Union University in the south suburb of Chengtu. Next, Pao-Pei arrives in Hong Kong at Kai Tak Airport in the custody of Dr. Gordan Campbell, Head of the Dental School at West China Union University. On sun deck of Empress of India en route Honolulu and Canada; Mr. Vierheller, Director St. Louis meets with Trustee Lemp; stopover in Denver; arrival of Pao Pei at St. Louis Airport. Escort Paul C. Domke bids animal farewell at Panda pit in St. Louis Zoo.
  - "Mong Hsien Talk, Oberlin in Shanghai", undated (Film Shelf)
  - "Angkor Wat, Hong Kong, Macau", July 1939 (Film Shelf)